good hello welcome everybody pretty exciting keno this morning.
So, if you don't realize...you stumbled into the native ui framework talk so happy
to see here my name is joe segment I'll be...session guide if you will for the next hour
and I'm talking about new features in the ui platform for a building I think we're
calling them now universal windows apps.
So, with that let me go ahead and get my clicker hearing...organized.
So, please submit evaluations
their super important overall for the conference as well as for me and for this talk.
And, plus you get a free prize I...there's a drawing for free prize which maybe know what it
is I don't so starting write-off I really can't see the audience from
...try anyway does...not know what
...me I see somebody's hand kinda go up
...this slide for use don't feel bad side is just free now maybe they were just waving
...each other okay anyway it is the if no,
one really is new to it then I won't spend time on it is basically the native
...I platform for the system and
...what we use for building by native I mean it chips with the platform
...what the first part experiences in the shells used to
...their experiences and
...what anybody building and native app typically uses to build-out there user interface and
by user interface I mean buttons sliders list those sorts of things tad
internet activity to the app experience example is all about that so, you saw
on windows...a lot of things this morning...keynote just a ton of things but, one of
the main things about hitting at whatever three billion number and some huge number in the next couple
years a devices...and that super important for windows but what we're trying to do across the
depth plat and including across...framework is want to make it easier
for you to take your experiences and delivered those across
all those endpoints so, there's some things we can do related to
just a unify platform but they're actually other things we can do to make it easier for you to be able to
adaptor experience based on the device or some other characteristic so I'm
going to talk about both those later on in this in this talk part of also, you know,
having this broader if you will set of devices that even if you're
somebody who's only targeting let's say mobile we've increased on our side of increase the ecosystem
so if you're only targeting mobile that means there's more code samples out there there's more people actually banging on
the platform make it faster making it better so even targeting just one device
this broader ecosystem is really goodness for everybody so we did a bunch of stuff around
universal windows apps but also we did other stuff around
...just basic talking to customers and they said hey I want this or I want that and,
if you wondering the second...is not a carries christmas card to me is
...than that sarah and actually I'm just joking was the birthday...was...but,
that's actually showing inc off in that one
I'll give you a quick demo that later on the talk but we did we try to talk to customers events
like this we go me customers we look at forms we know there's a lot we can do with the native
...I platform so we try to incorporate some of that feedback as well into this release.
So, that is a dev conference so
how about a starting off with a dev.
Demo I've got like...little options to pick up here and I think I got
the right one visual studio.
...to do...project I'll do this once today
...project and guess what you see I've selected in this case csharp.
Windows, windows universal there's not a phone project there's not, you know,
some sort of multi headed project...xbox project, you know,
there's not io t project there's one universal project
now you may choose to only deploy it...when you go to the store...side or you may choose
the only ship it to one set of devices but the platform really is the same
...the same across everything so finally project is just it's a file new universal
...all over endpoints so let's do how about
a hello world project because those are always fun now this
is a...once because...takes a little bit of time so why setting up
...things I want to show you as I clicked in a far-right corner and
bring up the new if you will see a countering experience that
...more touch friendly than what you might have on your...one systems...previous systems
...some of you may know who are familiar example that currently today we don't actually have a calendar control
in the platform so I thought would be fun for the hello world experience
would be to actually try to build-out this kind of experience ec
it's very touch friendly it's really nicezoom in zoom out so it
will be a bit of a challenge but, let's go ahead and give it a shot.
So, I'm going to come back to the designed...minute so...universal
project should run ideally should run everywhere so let me start
take a look at this thing again...what I'm doing here the...calendar view.
Margin equals twenty.
Vertical lambda equals tub.
...see that's go looking design you now.
It looks pretty good.
And, that's how easy it is so.
Go ahead and run it to show you this is...
...counter control I just...in a feature there
...few people requested it was like number two hundred-something on some things somewhere
let's see control.
Seriously.
Goes higher up and others.
But, I did look it up so,
I'm having a five I'm going to run this locally even though just you saw
it the exact same.
Exact same control down here we didn't make it and what we did
a windows ten is that basically all the inbox experiences are using example
develop their experiences so no more going how do they do that it
actually did it using the same platform that you're using so here you see super simple
calendar control I won't...through the counter experience but want to show you is to universe
...so let's go ahead and
show some universal action here I'm going to pick arm and I'm
keeping it reels here if you will I may regret this but
I'm going-to go ahead and run this now on my
real device and I'm going to project my screen so I'm going
...crazier?
So, this is my it's my engineering phone half...as my
...phone and again I'll do this whole deployment first-time once
like right now I have to just kinda...I know it's I know it's doing the right thing but I'm so in-patient I just
got a look.
So, yes, it is deploying
again I'll do this sort of fold cycle just to kinda show you that it's real just a couple times...ago.
Here's the experience exact same experience not a separate head exact same example file
now but we'll be running on my phone and you see it's all nice and touch friendly and I can do all the
exact same stuff and I can swipe but exact same experience here
...phone and across my desktop experience so,
you know, that's pretty cool it's one control so now I'm going to do my julia child and
I'm going to open up an existing app I have this really is more universal
controls what I've done here is really is almost zero code
an art the only code in this experience and run
...real quick the only code in this experience is that I wired up.
Something to basically open close the left pain.
And, I made it so that when I click on the when he's left
...things I reload different page here but that's really all I've done in
this app experience and I don't know why it's taken a minute here to build.
This is basically all taken pretty much a whole set of common
controls and just put them into and untouched the all the
...controls into this one app and we'll show you the experience running on a couple
different form factors that but again there's no platform optimizations here
this...thing pops up...showing you is
well first of all you can see there's a slightly updated branding and part of that was because now that would bring it
to hollow...phone and a few other devices we needed
make sure had something that was consistent across all those so we had to do some updates
...worth comptroller et cetera et cetera but here you see,
you know, not just all the controls working as you'd expect with a slightly updated branding
...suggest box working some slightly updated day-time pickers.
some other controls now what I want to show you here...desktop.
Have a command bar with overflows we've made people familiar command...see that's we made
some updates to the command bar too many updates me to go through all of them but one thing I want to show
here is going to click here and I added a we at
...menu and you see a couple things people familiar the platform one we added cascading which is nice
...it actually on desktop and other windows apps it goes outside the window which is which
is nice but we've done otherwise snipes little things we could do on which is I just it with my finger and now
you see we actually increase the spacing on that context menu
when I actually hit with my finger so where possible we've actually tried to put things in the platform that
kind of do the right thing where it's likely not going to impact the developer so let's say we made all controls
bigger on phone...smaller on desktop you're going to have to think about layout now so we
try to make a good-size that works well everywhere and cases where we could do this we
kind of light up the right behavior where you don't have to think about it or it won't get any way we did that
as well so let's go ahead and take this one step further and do the
...deployment here and I'll show you at running on
my phone and you see the same experience so won't take a lot of time here?
Project my phone...
Now one thing right away you go hey that's kind of a crappy experience and,
that has nothing to do with hamburger is that I really had to
give you default experience here this is one of things I'll talk about later...my talk which is
...sometimes even though I'm going to show you all the controls it's in a
...grid which is why it's a single...here if I actually do it
landscaping case you think I've got a different view here doing any magic exact same desktop
view but the how I interact with it going through the menu here is less
than ideal and I'll talk about how you can fix that later on the talk bc all the controls work
the same way but when you to other controls now hit the fly out you see
has the wide spacing like it should and...app are command bar you see
...actual edge to edge because we can do that it's slightly better on mobile and use a deb don't have to think
about it so nice experience with all the controls everywhere but you sort of
our promise here was not just about these two devices but a
couple devices so what I'm going to do here is anybody who came
...a little earlier I'm not sure anybody did come
...early...sorry the reason this is blurry is not because of anything to
do the system it's because I'm go on my xbox one here html I out to
va to this little box and as a result of all that it's got less than optimal
experience this is the same map and literally I just deployed it...right before I came in here
just to make sure we didn't have any issues exactly map experience working with controller?
And, one thing we're still fixing is focus on...super importance...light up focus
...right now on agile planning on having a...toggle agile planning but you can see
...to check box all the controls just work the way you expected
...are simple controls but I can come into the of
...just box hit a and I can go down
get this the sip and I can do exactly like what my desktop experience
it be to get out of there I'm going back to choose...here on there
we go she say this never crashes or other and uci going
...common box and interact by default I did nothing to light of this
experience it just works that doesn't mean you don't need to tailor you might not want to tailor
...that exact same experience works on xbox.
there's the app running there but I've deployed it to one other device so,
let's try this one and see if that's correct.
Again, exact same exact same app now it's running on this raspberry
...to my exact same app.
I may want to tailor just to show you is the
exact same experience working on this device done nothing just deployed
in everything works exactly the same I don't have a keyboard hooked up to
a but if I did I be able to show you more interactivity in this but that's really what we've done here is
really taken this common platform no...and...
big dot net no you gotta do a tricky different version
is the same thing run across all these different endpoints and we've really tried to make the controls
were great across all those different endpoints tailoring those different story and that's what
...spend a lot of the rest of my talk I'm talking about the tailoring...to this so.
With that.
I'll get back to the dec so one thing I do want to mention is that, you know,
people how many people built-in aone app say when universe
...some folks so as part of that you probably used to this experience where
you create multiple heads one for phone and one for desktop which don't have to do now
...part of that is that sometimes the controls they were there is similar
but slightly different so we had a take all those rough edges and kind of sand them off but that means
some times we had cases like password box where the default experience
for was just different crossed windows desktop and windows phone
didn't have it on desktop and...on xbox...have to worry about it where cases like this
...had to pick a...and do something about it so what we did I guess I can use
the clicker here is that just to let-you know that in those cases we picked the default behavior
and the way we pick the default behavior is we basically took a bunch
of data that we got from people using the experience we put in the cloud we did
a bunch analytics on it we had our data scientist poke and prod on it and it's this out this is what you should
do this I think that's what we did I just picked behavior but I'm not
...the first one and, we anyway...result is we had to
pick a behavior and then the end result is that sometimes you're stuck in which we
...the all phone behavior and some people may love that...the old windows behavior
they may love that so how do we deal with that so on those cases we end up having the
at another property that says hey which
behavior do you want and if you're going to build a windows ten head on top of your
if you want to build a windows ten head-on top your existing eight one app and you start with...assets
than...are things like this that you're going to have to know about and there's a talk on friday by sam
darwin who's actually go into this in detail but I'm not but on
the way to getting to universal apps we had some?
Pleasant.
Pleasant trees fall out of that and that we had controls
that only lived on one or the other so for those things.
We...either do nothing or we could say hey let's just
make and universal and pivot is a signature control,
control on phone and we looked at that...I said it feels like a really touch centric
...no this thing can were great with mouse and keyboard all we need to do is we
add some flippers to make it work with mouse and keyboard and
actually works like a tab like experience and we took a step further we made it so it could actually more
easily be branded to do a tab like experience whether you want to do that on phone or
desktop so we took this control we made it work well on desktop and
then we added some features to it and you see that's a common theme for next few
slides here content dialogue was another control that is was previously only on
phony one on windows there was something called
message dialogue or something like that but it didn't support example child content for people
or example people this does so this now you can use if you need to do a app
...stuff and it's again more powerful than what you might have been used to before
...what...suggest box was the way you do...complete if you will
...phone and unfortunate windows we had a different solution
called search box so that would created a tough one because we didn't want to convergent have
to things so,...pick which everyone you want so what we did is it
and they were both had slightly different behaviors so what we did is we took the good stuff
in search box which was it had some good aimee support search cliff we added those
...suggest box we still have search box but likely in the future we're going to deprecated and put
our investments into
a of suggest box and then maps there were like a nokia maps and
...a...maps and now they're just one maps with even more features and I believe there's a
talk that goes into detail on this either later today or next week so now also you got a
universal maps api which is kind of nice and with that that's kind of the I'll get on to
mostly net new stuff now but that's kind of the things that just fell out of us kind of getting to
one common core platform.
So, I mentioned before that we've really tried really hard to make it so that are controls actually really
were great everywhere and that means they work with...work on
you take app and runner as a holographic experience and it works iswhat
we call flat-out xbox controller we've tried to make it so use a developer don't have to
do anything there it doesn't mean if you're writing custom controls you won't have to do something but in general
we've really try to make it such that we don't think controls will
be you're dealing with controls across different devices if you will be a big issue for
developers what is going to probably be more of a big issue is that when you start thinking about
building those to using those controls to build-up more complex views and attached on this and the keynote
in my talk before this but you rarely maybe you come across...experience
like calculator where guess what one view works everywhere it's perfect
...five only one design but that's probably not the most
common thing so anybody who's used even...thirty-two programming
or used doing web programming knows that windows can be resize
...and this is an extension to that not only can windows be resize but now you
can run your window if you will exact same window on multiple devices with different
characteristics screen size being one of them so
use a developer you're going to probably want to do something to optimize are
tailor for that so we've tried inject some things into the platform to make that easier which is what
to talk about next and all this is a showing here which I think I'm going to do a demo of is that,
you know, things like secondary navigation actually let me just jump into the demos
...the picture read frame around me and a girl I photographed in
...shopped in there that is just showing that the screenshot
...the screens are the photo sizes actually smaller on...
it's actually literally it's actually smaller...photos experience here because they don't want to
...use much memory on that device so there's one about the navigation which is one of the
red boxes but that's what it was trying to show there but forget analysis jump
to just kinda show you what I really want to show you here?
Pick the right one.
Back here yes okay in my app
...a pop-up photos just real quick because you've and,
carrie and test on this a little bit but the main thing I want to show here is that this is an experience
...going to see a lot which is, you know,
as you resize the app adapts and in here...fire I'm
...up my phone which I'll show you in a minute but it's...get fired up so you have to wait for it to fire
up on phone but as a developer these are the kind of things that you
even on desktop...a desktop I have to worry about resize
ing so there are certain things that you're likely going to want to be able to do to your app and one of the things in the first thing
...all talk about is you are seeing and I'm not going to
...for the hamburger pattern because we don't bake in if you will the hamburger pattern
per say into...control what I do want to say is there are times where
you have secondary commands like navigation commands here and
...important in a great to see when you have enough space but when you don't have
enough space those are the kind of things especially in photos where you want to
...pictures of something like my beautiful wife here that you want to hide those
instill making available through a secondary ux affords in the case here.
You can see the affords is now
...popped out I've got a pop out and...the main features one of
features that we added in windows ten that I'll show is a feature called split view
it basically enables this experience in fact that's what photos uses which is I can create a
...a secondary...which is actually this pane over here with collections
through settings and I can take that...based on my size I can basically put
it into a overlay mode and make it pop out there secondary
affords and I'm going to just quickly just jump over and show you that same experience.
Running here on my phone this is you can see from...running the exact same photos app is the photos app
...comes in-box you can see here microsoft where we're going to kool-aid the same
app here clear...same app...experience same stuff
...the default experience I get here is that everything on my phone which you can see on
the screen experience the default experience I get here is there's less space so
...smaller images and...go into an overlay mode further if you will
their split view so what we've done in the...we've tried to look at those kinds of patterns and
we said hey what can we do to make it easier for developers to build those kind of patterns.
So, jumping back to my
mind dec here there's a couple things that we've done and the first one I just did
this the first one is the split view which I just talked about and just
a demo of so on...a lot of time here but there's really said
...a secondary...which you can kind of hide and make fly out ...there's a
primary content area but the other thing is that you start thinking how...as developer
...powerless how're...where you rules so you just writing code that says look
at windows size and when I see windows size do this or their better
way to do that sort of thing so what we've done is we've kinda looked at other solutions in the industry
we thought a lot about it so we've got this new feature which is basically adaptive triggers
and setters or it's really an extension of the sm for people on the web world
are kinda used to media queries it's like annexed really extensible version of that but effectively
use a developer can set up rules in here as an...trigger that says we have
built-in size rules like when the windows this size do that...effectively with what you
can with the rules but the declarative so one they're easy to define
and to the design tool can actually help you do this and I'll say in
the current version the designer helping you do this
or that design solution for this is not online yet but that the reason that we've done
a declarative...so the designer can actually do this so what the rules are saying here the bottom
role is saying effectively
hey when my sizes between zero and seven twenty which is the top
role I want to set the set of properties but I want to do these actions and...top
one is saying seven twenty beyond do these sets of actions now the trigger itself I said we
built-in with rules screen with rules but there's a talk tomorrow
by team your and hurriedly we're going to talk about this and much more detail they're going to talk about how you
can actually create and define your own triggers and then you can define
own rules for what happens when one of those triggers is actually hit so this
is a really super powerful way...really easily define the rules that allow you to sort of
adaptor app so the other thing we've done?
Is I'm in a jump back star for the disjoint nature here let's jump
back and look at while I'm on the phone here I'm
a pop-up settings...see that comes up quickly?
If it does.
Here's settings this little thing a settings on my phone and
...to bring up settings.
On my big display now mega hey those
are different experiences but I'm going to resize on and boom
the desktop one actually just turned into it's the
same app even again I'm windows were doing the exact same thing it's just when I sizes smaller
it reacts differently it lays out differently but this is a little more advanced than what I showed
before split view and what's the more...if you see find a setting here one thing
is watched the text you see it pops up so it kind of moves...kind of changes
their bit the other one is other than this icon being different
has its phone all the rest of the same you can see on in the phone is
icon text next to it kind of two-column layout and my phone just went to sleep
...and on desktop watch when I switch.
The mode is now I've gone exact same tax but now it's kind of in a vertical layout so
here I've done a actual layout switch rather than just a simple setting a
property switch so what we've done in ten
Again, taking a look at that is we've added a new panel to help assist
in those kind of scenarios so...familiar with android they might be familiar with
...relative panel layout that they have their kind of a similar thing so this is showing us
my actually next sample that I'm going to show if you're sample developer you probably
tried to lay something out like this before using some combo of grids
in stack panels and even then you may not be able to get quite right so
that looks pretty simple it's just an image with three things text in a button
...they want to get that button aligned to the bottom or things like that can sometimes be
...a bit of a challenge and it does require what we call nested
panels and nested panel's aren't necessarily a bad thing but it turns out if
you're displaying hundreds of images your creating a lot of extra elements if
you will and as a...is are and curing kumar doing a talk I think tomorrow
we're talking about perf if you want to...as fast as possible if you want to
pan as fast as possible these little things about using extra elements can start
to slow you down so what would be great would be if there was a better way to define this and that's what
relative...about so take the exact same layout image?
Now I can add my next text block and I say hey I want this to be to the right
of the image and aligned with the top the image and I want my
authors to be aligned to the right the image and below the title.
It took me for somebody has to asleep and I clearly am.
Okay, that was the previous one I showed which was the nested...moving forward.
this is relative panel image on the left so the same view that I previously
showed...like how do you can...I was trying to do...since I didn't.
...trying to show how to build this experience off on the right and the first slide
...showing how you would do this using grid...stack panels which is the traditional way might do it
...and it's hard to do things like align the bottom button some shown exact same experience and how
you build it using relative panel and with relative panel you would use
...stick your image in it you would say my text blocks title and you would say is
...of the image
...with the top of the image and the next text block is just aligned to
the ready image again and below the previous one same thing with summary
of the image but below the authors and in the last one the button a is to the
...image but alignment...I could do with the bottom of the panel or to the
right image so really more complex layout but easier to
do with relatively out panel and then you start thinking about this...the setter thing
I talked about before the kinds of wild things that you could do in terms
of in response to something like a layout change become super powerful to be able to
changer layouts dynamically previously you might have had to do some weird stuff
...changing columns and that sort of thing...in a grid no longer
you-can use this and it turns out it solves the kind of scenarios that I previously showed
with settings so with that I actually want to show jump back to do this correct this time?
I will jump back to my demo machine and let's go ahead and just show you this
stuff in real action here as I get rid of all this.
And, get rid of my previous one...open a project.
And, effectively this-is.
It's the simplest product you've ever seen it doesn't maybe you will look at think
it's that simple but it turns out it really is super simple it is stack
...top with an icon that's my ux affords for opening up you don't see anything here
because it's all data bound for ava split view there's the panel
...and there's the content area so let's go ahead and
...all data bound from ...going data from a service the
services filling up this list on the left and it's doing the same thing based on
what I select here it's going off and grabbing a service and data binding this stuff...actually show you this
animal for this is super simple literally it's less than a
hundred lines of amr code to do all of this experience most people have used
...for can contain that's not exaggeration so,
...I want to show here is that you'll notice I'm running the same experience I showed
in my the first demo I did with the controls and that as a resize this down
...run on the phone you can see this experience one that doesn't
gets I really like that to go in and overflow mode this but view
to you can see that text does not look ideal here so it
starts to overlap stuff that's ideally I'd like to fix that as well so,
those are two things I go, you know, I'd love to fix those and if you're...developer you
...it how would you how would you do that in your app experience and
I I'm guessing what you would probably do is going to be more complex...show you here maybe not this
...clever people...docked people can come up with a
saying that my expert this is really pretty simple there's a command
...the bottom I've.
Just had these just to make...easy-to-read but that's
the details view that's the navigation pane right there data bound and this right
here's the stack panel that holds my ux affords I said we didn't build in
the hamburger pattern you actually have to add your ux affords I've added a three icon or
three bar icon that opens and...that's really the only code of added here when I click that button
...close so I pre can daniela thing in here is
...canned in those visual stateside to showed you so
on uncommon it and what I've...wired up here it's the only thing I've changed here is I've just
added these new visual triggers and I say here is...my sizes
between zero and seven twenty that I want my display mode
basically the overlay and I want to...default to closed and
...seven twenty above make it open and I could do this and say I want only...that
...mobile I could add my own if you will triggers that are not just min width
...could be something else but, now just keep it simple I've just done
it based on size so that was step a that I wanted to fix and?
I'll just because it won't take me much to show you that on desktop and I'll come back and
showdown phone so just run it now with those couple lines of code.
Boom that simple super use do that...changed really there's nothing up nicely
that was all it took so just to keep it real I'm going to show you one
more but this one and trying to.
Show you real experience hear this second one is in a data...people,
for example, no, that's a way that you generate ui in a
data bound way right now we have not wired up the triggers yet
to work and data templates but so like I said I'm try to keep
...real but how to get around that most really simple all it is
...blank user control for...user controls
other ways you can create you reusable components of ui example but this is
an empty blank user control I'm just going to take my data template
...on my data template.
Stop...your demo okay let's go back I just want
my relative panel that's all I want.
Thank you and go back to my view I just want the relative panel.
That's it that looks good and now my user control is named.
Book item view so local.
All I did is I just shove that in
the user control my apple now run exactly the same way that's all I did.
But, I want to show you that.
Additional piece of adaptability so let's go ahead and copy what I did
...put inbook item view at the beginning here.
But, I don't really want to split view display mode I want to do.
I want to fix that text overflow problem so that text is actually it's this property here
summary that's that one it tends to get long and what I would like to do is I would just like to set the
maximum...line some ado summary?
Of a set max lines.
...normal situational save five sounds good and.
Will copy that each and redo that same rule down below but in
a zero to seven twenty case I want...science to bthree?
And, let's go ahead and let's shoot for the whole ball of wax
let's run this on mobile so you get to see the full experience on mobile.
Yes, I do want to project.
So, if you remember before it would come up side-by-side
but mobile now you can see I'm not side-by-side awesome and
look at the text up something didn't work.
Look, at that.
What did I do wrong?
Thank you love having a smart audience it is...
Thank you rain man.
I only know avce no fence it's...argue that.
If ...money back at the back I'm sorry.
There thank you thank you that person over there...help with my demo so,
there you see it now on here I see the get there.
Okay, I saw it I was excited.
...my trick was to pretend like it was working it really wasn't so boy see I love
my technology is so cool so there you see now see now you can
...yeah, this is a.
And, it really was it really was that simple to do I really try to take a real sample to build that
out for people who care I have one more...that I'm not going to make now but it's the same I do a
couple more lines and actually move that ux affords from the top-down into the command bar
went on...same using the same trigger for people who really want to make
sure ux that don't like hamburger and the reaching...with hamburger have a command
are down here and I just...the ux affords down there under the same trigger it was super
easy to do so with that let me switch back and.
Go...powerpoint and talk about some other things that we've done.
My on the right thing yes.
So, performance I mention there is a talk tomorrow on performance by...and
...kumar and one thing about performance
that is interesting is that I mention that all of our experiences kind of moved over to
example and that's really great for everybody and that now when you see something
...hey, you know, you should be able to the exact same thing there was no cheating internally
by providing the first parser general experiences and...them to do something you
...third-party can't do but the side effect for our team was that's good for you is that
hey that the shells running all the times run twenty four seven and that thing when I had to start
menu that starts being better come up and better not be taken on my memory...the system and,
I...better be blazing the fast so before when the shells
...sort of default to having their own framework in some cases it allowed us to
not necessarily keep the performance metrics we would need for really super high-performance
needs like the shell so what we did is we had to spend a lot of time on just
makings animal as lean and trim as possible.
And, with that there's a set of things and I guess I don't talk about my next slide but
mark internal talk about there's a set of things that if you just take your existing
aone app and run on windows ten it's faster because we just had to do a bunch of
just general performance stuff in the engine there's another set of things when you recompile for windows
...app gets faster and that's because when you compile we kind of turn example into a
fast node stream and we made that...so much better on windows ten after
we target to get that up so it's really a much more better binary format if you will and
then there were some things where we just couldn't find any way to just make it implicit
and we had to have people opt into so there's one of those I want to talk about because it turns out the side effect of
it's actually really good developer value...something called compile bindings so
what are things we noticed is bindings are inherently string based in anybody
whose had a binding where they...the name wrong and everything compiled and worked in your apt
in runny didn't know why because runtime we're doing to look up and if the
look up doesn't work sometimes return exception...sometimes you never see it and,
it can be painful but also guess what it can be slow
...actually using reflection to do that look up and attic cpu and
that takes memory so, our first thought was which is a great thought we said
bindings...evil let's have nobody used bindings and everything
...get faster and you think I'm joking and?
We're I going are developers...smartness cplus-plus guys of get it guys and gals emit
...a general mutual general term so,
again, the...money back sorry about that so,
we literally did...we actually said don't...bindings but we've been told
...still do it cycle this is not working what can we do so after some
thinking it turns out that we can actually result bindings...compile-time we can basically just turn
them into loosely property sets we change notification we need to
...it turns out not only that a lot faster and a lot faster it turns
out when you type name wrong...your binding you now get a compiler check.
other things that fell out now it's pretty easy for us to just wire up go ahead one so,
effectively what you need to do to move the bindings is we did have to
change the syntax but we try to keep it as compatible as possible you do have to say
...data template you may have to say here's my type combining...which you should know what your type is
...than that you just change binding the x columbine and now though side effect
that to is audio compile-time checking things like event handlers
you can now wire up directly with x combined so we actually have new features in
there as well so this is as I said it start out as a perf feature started as we try to kill
a feature and end up as a pretty nice feature that we all feel pretty good about it so definitely try that
out the...spencer I think as a talk right after this where he's
...into we deep on this one other nice side effect of this
is I mention we compile-time we generate all this we actually
...a form of cs files you can actually single step to your bindings now the code that we used
to do reflection those hidden in the framework you can actually step through now to see what's going on with your
binding so super powerful love the feature so other things we did that didn't fall out of
perf this is just a smattering of...long list but just a set of
for the highlights for people who have done tricks?
In the past where they want to know in something changes like visibility on
element changes are when something else happens and we don't provide change
notification that property some people in the past and tricks where they hook up element,
element binding to their own dp and figure out that way anyway so that's kinda of
crazy we'll just have a property now on our all dp so you can basically
hook change notification on pretty much any ui property now which again is something that we've
heard lots of people ask for the past this next one if I if you are
...have windows ten installed and...hit the start screen when it first comes up you see all the tiles
...this fancy three-d stuff and some people maybe going hey but you support perspective
transform we do in the thing about perspective transform as you can transform anyone element
in three-d space you want to do multiple elements in three-d space you transform both of them
and then if you want to animate those you have to separate animations rn animations to animate
all of those you want to do some kind of camera on top of those good luck you better be
a rocket scientist because it's really hard so we basically have a compose
...way to do that where you can sort of said if you will camera and you could set perspectives
at multiple levels which makes these kinds of things so much easier
and I won't show...a demo this I'll just show you the demo and probably not going
to code that it super easy might my demos actually all market demo?
Window
...doing apps running a windows back on the desktop tool yes hi...
But, as part of that so you expect now to be able to custom chrome but if you're going to be
doing custom chrome user way we can...that up and hey,
there is a actually away it's really easy you first of all it's easy
to branding on your chrome you cannot change the background foregone color but
you take a step further you can actually define a little example snippet in your
page and you can basically annotate that example snippet and you can
say hey please use this example as my custom chrome and you put that
anywhere your page actually and that's the
thing that you can use to move around your app and resize your app
...powerful...to custom chrome you can do it just using declared
...market then I'll actually show you a demo
...exactly just that and it...hard so here's
...creepy christmas photo to me but this is just showing we added
we have a way to...in the platform as a may tried doing a high-fidelity
inc experience before couple people how
...good you privacy smart so but,
it's not always the easiest thing so ...kind of
been overhauled updated and doesn't do things like pom rejection so
if you actually have somebody's like an artist to touches the...on
...existing solution didn't do that but we've got a new control calling canvas it's just that easy
shove it in and ...inkling and,
there's a talk that talks about this in a lot of detail you get the strokes and smoothing lots
of stuff it's really cool it's really super powerful and drag-and-drop they
showed this morning in the keynote drag-and-drop super easy now we can
drag from the desktop drop in your app advice for students see of people
...wintry to drag-and-drop this
is like that only easier it's just super simple to do so with that let's see I got
forty minutes to get one more good demo that I want to show after I show you this over here my last demos
...funnel demo?
Which is not this one this one's not bad either?
Ok, so, everybody can see good.
Want to make the same mistake again will coliseum this one.
So, what I've done here you see
and design view is basically?
Run this app.
I basically taken and use the perspective transform.
And, now, for example, is all mark-up except for doing the animation
it super simple to do and you're seeing some drawing artifacts but it's all
these are real three-d cubes and
...so simple to do this...each one is cubes is...analyst
reused but, these sort of experiences become super simple with a new three-d api
...and here's my custom chrome that's just image element example that I
said action...an icon...example that I just said hey please use this
as my chrome and that's my chrome that's our move us...size and
it's in the sample is so simple it's really I liked it
...to tell you that it super hard but it turns out that it's actually not super hard to do and,
all my main heavy lifting the top is all this is basically what
...use display each one of those cubes the top...my animation but this is
...right here it's this code you just creating the sides?
Each one of those a...that's all it is and I'm just putting a transform and each one and
animated...layer higher so it's really turns out it's super easy to do but what I want to do is
on keep this running because I want to use this for my next
But, I'll get back to powerpoint intro my next demo which would be my final one.
So, we've done a bunch of enhancements to you saw the new
...with the edge engine today so it's no longer project spartan but I didn't
update this slide...left in the teaser...
Anyway, my own clever trick that's not very clever but,
anyway, there's a bunch of enhancements the access you...when rt that they showed today
...the keynote us...am...can host a web view and that web
...turn-around access when rt but there's a bunch of other things that have been down to the web view there's
a session tomorrow I believe kevin hill or somebody can tell me when it is I think
we're sitting over here there's...talks about all the new great stuff that's...the web you control that applied
years am lap and then there are some improvements
...visual studio you saw
a little bit today I think about how you can resize your experience...
You can resize the experience in the designer its this experience here.
Since we only have one universal app now you can preview it on hey what is a...on
...phone which this does work on
the phone and that's fit to screen.
But, you can oahu.
That's not what I wanted
...goes sixty hello there it's in there somewhere okay...pick...pick io
...or I mean a surface.
...should...there is so gives an idea of what would look like
...surface habit there's some features like this where you can do portrait landscape across all the devices
in design view since you don't have individual ones.
And, I'll come back to that later show you a different demo on that same
one so that's.
That's one of the things that we've done we've also done a new...the first image
...timeline tool which I think martin
...talk about...the...tools and greatly enhanced
and super powerful but the last...of...and on...kind of a fun little one which is
a visual tree inspector so let me just show you that in action.
So, people who are you know, use we use web tools will know that.
what cfb confuse myself here okay where is my.
Boy what have I done.
I just turned off my view that I wanted and you know,
what you would...I know-how to turn it back on that?
Windows live asks.
...now we're getting back in.
You know, what while I'm doing this actually let me show you a different...show
the feature different way you can tell me whether this is good or not...you show you my previous app?
And, I'm going to attach.
Again, you tell me this is a good thing or not.
...I just did.
...some...ds in a way that's like that's not a good thing.
Seymour positively I feel better about my demo right now yes.
effectively you get to see primarily in your app this is not the
...would only be good in this kind of experience if you want to go I want to know what icon they're using
not if you want to know how they're actually doing it this is a really great thing in your own app experience
...how is that margin words that margin getting set because what this does it basically gives you the full
if you will example visual tree and that's what you see anal left here and what you can do which is
what...my previous app experience is you can actually go and select individual item and go
hey so what's the what's the color they use on that fonts?
And, you can actually find out it's solid color brush.
And, there's the actual color use apparently transparent but you can
act and you can actually interact with it so I can change.
Real time to go hey.
...I picked the wrong one I'm going I'm going to,
you know, I'm going to go back to my other app because that's the one I knew how to do this since I got...
Nope, not that one.
That's that one of work.
It will work.
Because primarily the big value is a lot of times people who are familiar and use animal sometimes are going
...what is going on here how is that.
How is that getting set and this will tell you whether it's coming from a style there we go so,
let's go ahead and I could...like how is
...soon how is that...said and what is it and you'll see a
keep for myself by?
Changing my chrome.
it over here the visual tree inspector will tell me what was text blocking tell me what size it is
...whether not set from a style and I must...clicked on something else I
...this is great for multi monde it's kind of tougher with single on term
iverson it tells me it's set from style.
In apt...tells me all the settings...that style but...I want to show you two is I clicked on
the image background and there's the transform three-d here and I'm going to set the z
you can actually interact with it all set to minus three that's...four hundred.
So, I just push that image back into it to show you the kind of
affects you can generate with ...click on this which make my app go away but I'll just show you what I just
did so real-time negative paradox effect going on because I just take that image with
our new transform three-d stuff and I just pushed it back three hundred effective pixels in the
...order and now you can say get this nice
...clever experience but in general this debugging tool
...super powerful I use it all the time distant even building simple apps remote why
is that margin why is that...couple pixels and now you can go through
and click on something go through the whole visual tree and sorry I got because I'm not multi
monde I could go through the whole visual tree as text block within a lips on top of it
...grid integrated...verbal size...create and I go any one of these
and check what are the margins...the settings so becomes a super powerful way to figure out what's kind of really
going on with your with your app and with that I think.
Did that they're a bunch of other things that we've done...didn't go over but
there are some cases these are covered by other session certainly be covered in the...but a lot of other things
up in the on this related sessions listed here as I mentioned a couple
these the data binding and zambia performance there's
a hurrying tim gotta talk tomorrow on...adaptability in-depth?
Session valuation please and with that thank
you everybody appreciate you come and what about native ui?
And, I'll stick around for questions.